<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science | Academic</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/category/science/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/category/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Science</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/category/science/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific programming languages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/post8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/post8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-programming-languages-are-widely-represented-in-science&#34;&gt;What programming languages ​​are widely represented in science?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is one of the most powerful and flexible languages ​​that is also widely used in data science. The main reason is its simple and elegant syntax, as well as a large collection of third-party libraries. A tool that can be found all over the data science field is Jupyter. Jupyter notebooks let you quickly see the results of your code, plot your data, and create code documentation using markup blocks. It is not a Python-only tool, but the most common combination is Python and Jupyter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R is an open-source programming language first introduced in 1993 and used for statistical computing, data analysis, and machine learning. According to Stack Overflow analysis, R&amp;rsquo;s popularity has been growing over the past few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although R is widely used by researchers, it is now also used by large technology companies such as Google, Facebook and Twitter for data analysis and statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Julia takes the best of languages ​​like Python, Ruby, Lisp, and R, combines it with the speed of C, and includes familiar math notation like Matlab. We can call Julia an ambitious attempt to create a language that is good enough for general programming and at the same time amazing for specific computer science disciplines such as machine learning, data mining, distributed and parallel computing. One of the main advantages of Julia is its speed, comparable to languages ​​such as C, Rust, Lua and Go. This is because it is compiled using the Just-In-Time (JIT) principle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MATLAB is a proprietary programming language used by millions of engineers and scientists for mathematical and statistical computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scala is a high-level programming language first introduced in 2004 that runs in the JVM (Java Virtual Machine) or with JavaScript in your browser. Many data scientists have included Scala in their toolkit because it is invaluable when it comes to analyzing large amounts of data. According to the Stack Overflow 2021 study, Scala is the 7th highest paid language in the world. But you need to be careful with these statistics, since working in Scala is not that common in the industry. Since Scala runs on the JVM, you&amp;rsquo;ll have access to a ton of existing libraries and some Scala-only packages used in the fields of big data, mathematics, databases, and computer science in general. If you&amp;rsquo;re already fluent in Java, Scala may be the right language for you to transition into data science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java has been one of the most common and beloved programming languages ​​for several decades. It is a universal language that can be used in almost every situation imaginable. Data science is no exception. Although Java is primarily used in mobile and web applications, due to its strong user base, it is used along with other popular frameworks such as Hadoop or Spark for analyzing large volumes of data.
Java can be used in most areas of data science such as database management, machine learning. If you know Java, it is much easier to master a couple of libraries than to learn to use a completely different language like R or Julia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The C++ language completes this list. Although it is used primarily to create applications and operating systems, without it we would not have seen the current rise of data science. Data scientists prefer languages ​​like Python or R that are easy to use and debug because they don&amp;rsquo;t want to waste time fixing weird bugs in C/C++. However, C++ plays an important role in data science because many libraries used in other languages ​​are written in it. Building a machine learning model requires computational effort, so using an efficient language like C++ makes sense. If you want to get involved in the data science industry by developing libraries for other languages, C++ may be the right choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
